All right, all right, all right, let's play one more time, ok?
좋아 좋아
한 번만 더 해보자
And remember, if I win you do not move to Paris.
내가 이기면
너 파리에 안가는거다?
Ok! Can't believe I'm risking this again, but you're on!
그래, 내가 이런
위험한 내기를 또 하다니
그래도 해보지 뭐
All right Joe, you remember the rules! Heads I win, tails you lose.
조이, 규칙 기억하고 있지?
앞면이면 내가 이긴거고
뒷면이면 네가 지는거다
던지기나 해!
Just flip!
뒷면이다!
Ha, tails!
/ Damnit!
이런 젠장!
Hey!
/ Hey!
레이첼, 너 송별회 파티
7시쯤에 해주려고
So we thought we'd throw you little going away party around seven.
와, 정말이야?
Oh, that sounds good!
레이첼, 너 내일 떠나는데
짐 싸야 되는거 아니야?
Hey, Rach, you're leaving tomorrow, shouldn't you be packing?
It's all done!
다 했어
물론 그러시겠지
Oh, yeah, right! And after I took a shower this morning I just threw my towel on the floor!
차라리 내가 오늘 아침 샤워하고
타월을 바닥에 떨어뜨렸다고 하지 그래?
Oh God, it hurts to even joke about it.
오, 이럴수가
농담으로 한건데도 마음이 아파!
I know... Honey, seriously, I did it all. The luggage that I'm taking is in the bedroom,
모니카, 나 정말로 다 해놨어
가져갈 짐은 침대방에 있고
이건 에마 물건이고
this is Emma's Paris stuff, these are the boxes that I'm having shipped,
이건 부칠 짐들이고...
비행기에서 먹으려고
샌드위치도 싸놨고
and that's the sandwich that I made for the plane...
Ok, so you've done some good work! What about your carry-ons?
그래, 잘 해놓긴 했어
그런데 비행기에 들고 들어갈 짐은?
Oh, well. Everything that I need is in here
필요한 건 다 여기다 넣어놨고
출국 관련 서류는 저기 카운터에
쓰일 순서대로 정리해놨어
and my travel documents are on the counter organized in the order that I will be needing them.
이럴수가!
더 이상 가르칠 게 없어!
Oh my God! I have nothing left to teach you!
Where's your passport?
여권은 어디다 뒀는데?
It should be right next to my plane ticket.
비행기표 옆에 있을거야
음, 없는데?
Well, it's not.
뭐? 어, 여기다 넣었나?
이럴수가! 여기도 없잖아!!
What? Maybe I put it in here. Oh, oh, it's not in there!
Oh, no! I must have packed it in one of these boxes!
안돼!! 나 짐 쌀 때
박스 안에 같이 넣어버렸나봐!
Here, let me help you.
내가 도와줄게
이런 일이!
내가 이런 짓을 하다니!
Shoot. Oh, I can't believe I did this!
At what point did it stop being funny that I took her passport?
어느 시점에서 농담을 그만두고
내가 감췄다고 말해야 되나?
FㆍRㆍIㆍEㆍNㆍDㆍS
10x16 The One With
Rachel's Going Away Party
[제 작]
코리아닷컴 프랜즈동호회 자막팀
[해 석]
김효진(with0124@korea.com)
[싱 커]
권순임(ksl7704@korea.com)
임의 수정 및 상업적용도의 사용을 금합니다
자막 피드백은 게시판을 이용해 주세요
(club.korea.com/friends)
3주 뒤면 아기가 나온다니
믿어져요?
Oh, wow, can you believe you're like three weeks away?
I know.
그러게요
You don't mind me touching your belly, do you?
배 만지는 거 싫지 않죠?
네, 배 만지는 건 괜찮아요
No, I don't mind you touching my belly,
but right now your hand is kind of blocking the part where the baby is gonna come out.
근데 지금 모니카 손은 아기가
나올 통로 쪽을 가로막고 있네요
안녕?
Hey!
/ Hi.
안녕?
Hey Erica, welcome back to town! Wow, look how big you've gotten.
다시 오셨네요!
와, 몸이 정말 커졌네요
임신해서 그런 거에요!
That's because I'm pregnant!
Right, no, I understand.
알아요, 저도 이해해요
Oh, ok. I'm just always afraid that people think I'm just fat with big breasts.
사람들이 절 그냥 뚱뚱하고
가슴 큰 여자로 볼까봐 걱정하고 있죠
No, no, I knew.
아니죠, 아니에요
전 알고 있었어요
Okay, well, stop staring at them.
오빠, 그만 쳐다봐!
저쪽에서 먼저 얘기 꺼낸 거잖아!
She brought them up! I didn't realize you were coming back so soon!
이렇게 빨리
다시 돌아올 줄은 몰랐네요
Yeah, well, in a couple of weeks I won't be able to travel.
예, 몇주 후면
여행하기 힘들테니까요
Yeah, and I wanted her to get to know the doctors and get settled into the hotel.
여기 와서 미리 의사도 만나보고
호텔에 자리잡을 여유도 있잖아
Hotel? Why isn't she staying with you guys?
호텔? 그냥 여기
너네 집에 묵게 하지 않고?
얼마 안 있다 이사할거니까
좀 그렇잖아
Because we're moving in a couple of days and it just didn't make sense.
Plus hotels are fun! My room has this little fridge full of free snacks!
전 호텔 좋아요!
방에 공짜 음식들 가득
들어있는 냉장고도 있고!
에리카, 그 음식들은
공짜가 아니에요
Erica, those things aren't free.
In fact they have one of the highest mark-ups of any consumer product...
마진율이 다른 어떤
소비품보다도 크다구요
오빠, 이 분은 우리한테
자기 아기를 주실 분이야
Ross! She's giving us her baby. She can eat you if she wants.
원한다면 오빠라도 먹게 할거야
금방 올게요
I'll be right back.
너희가 이 아파트를 떠나다니
믿을 수가 없어
Oh man, I can't believe you guys are leaving this place.
나도 그래, 나도...
Oh, I know. I know. Hey, you know, you can take it if you want!
이 아파트 원하면 오빠가 써도 돼
The lease is still in Nana's name.
아직도 할머니 이름으로
계약된 상태니까
아니야, 이 아파트는
언제까지나 너희 아파트야
No, no. This will always be your place. It would be too sad.
다른 사람이 쓰게 된다니
그건 슬퍼
게다가, 조이 먹여 살리는 데
한 달에 얼마 들지?
Plus, how much a month does it cost to feed Joey?
두 사람 수입이 필요하지
Yeah, it takes two incomes.
챈들러 지금 있니?
아까 영화 보러가잔 얘기했었는데
Hey, is Chandler here? We talked about catching a movie.
지금 챈들러 영화 볼 시간이
없을텐데
Oh, no. He doesn't have time for that.
But if you want, you can go help him and Joey pack up the guest room.
지금 챈들러랑 조이가 게스트룸
짐 싸고 있는데 오빠도 도와줄래?
Mhm, packing - sexy cheerleader comedy.
짐을 싸야 하나, 섹시한 치어리더
나오는 코메디를 봐야 하나?
Mhm, helpful brother - creepy loner at teen movie.
도움되는 오빠가 될래, 십대 영화에
헤벌레 하는 궁상남이 될래?
궁시렁 궁시렁~~
너네 지금 뭐 하는 거야?!
What are you guys doing?
너도 와서 해봐!
나 정말 하나도 안 아파!!
Try it, I can't feel a thing!
Are, are you kidding? This is packing?
지금 장난해?
지금 이게 짐 싸는 거야?
잠깐 쉬고 있는 거야
We're taking a break!
From?
뭐하다가?
침대에서 덤블링 하다가
Jumping on the bed?
All right, Rachel's party is in a couple of hours and there's a lot to do.
몇 시간 뒤면 레이첼 송별회인데
아직 할 일이 많단 말야
오빠도 겔러 집안 피가 흐르잖아
이 망나니들 오빠가 맡아
Now, Ross, you got Geller blood, you're in charge of these yahoos!
You got it! All right, she's right, we gotta get serious.
나한테 맡겨
좋아, 모니카 말이 맞아
장난치지 말고 진지하게 하자
이 포장 스티로폼을
조이 바지 안에 넣고 발로 차보자
Let's put styrofoam peanuts down his pants and kick him!
아냐 아냐, 모니카 말대로
지금은 일해야 돼
No, no, no, guys. She's right. We should get to work.
내가 옷장에서 물건들 꺼낼테니까
I'll take stuff out of the closet, Joey you pack 'em and Ross you re-pack whatever Joey packs.
조이, 네가 그걸 싸고, 로스
넌 조이가 싼 거 풀어서 다시 싸
You guys hear a ringing?
너희도 지금 벨소리가 들리니?
What the hell is this?
대체 이게 뭐야?
헤~ 수갑이잖아? 털장식까지!
Hey! Handcuffs! And fur line, nice! I didn't know you guys had it in ya!
너희가 이런거 갖고 있을줄 몰랐다
챈들러, 넌 여동생이 없어서
Chandler, you don't have a sister so you can't understand how much this bums me out.
지금 내가 얼마나
충격받았는지 모를거야
모니카가 이런 걸
갖고 있는 줄은 몰랐어
I didn't know Monica had these!
Mhm, maybe she used them with another boyfriend. Maybe Richard!
다른 남자친구랑 쓰나 보지
리차드랑 쓸지도 모르겠네
왜 리차드랑 이걸 쓰고
나랑은 안 써?
Why would she use them with Richard and not me? I can be kinky!
나도 변태스러워질 수 있다고!
모니카 앞에서 스카프만 하고
알몸 댄스를 춘 적도 있어!
I once did a naked dance for her... with scarves!
충격이야, 얘들아
충격이라고!
Bumming hard, guys, bumming hard.
안녕
Hey!
/ Hey! Where's Mike?
안녕, 마이크는 어디 갔어?
Oh, he has a gig. I kinda like being married to a rock star, you know.
오늘 공연 있거든
꼭 내가 인기 락커랑
결혼한 기분이야
"내 남편 공연 있어"
My husband has a gig.
Yeah? Yeah, where is it?
어디서 공연하는데?
Oh, he's playing organ for a children's roller-skating party.
어린이 롤러스케이트 파티에서
오르간 연주한대
Rock on!
멋지다!!
Wow, this is quite a spread! What is all this stuff?
와, 한 상 차렸네?
이게 다 뭐야?
Well, I thought this would be a great opportunity to use up all the food
이사 가면서 가져가고 싶지 않은
음식 재료들 다 써버릴 기회 같아서
that I don't want to move to the new house with me!
자, 맛있게 먹어!
So, enjoy: smoke oyster casserole with a breakfast cereal crust,
콘푸로스트 들어 있는
굴 구이 전골요리
kidney beans in their own juices, and for dessert, a questionable orange.
강낭콩과 그 콩즙
그리고 디저트로는...
의문스러운 오렌지!
얘들아
Hey.
/ Hey.
왔어?
Hey, where's Rach?
레이첼은?
Oh, she's putting Emma down, she'll be over in a second.
에마 재우고 있어
금방 올 거야
지금 레이첼이 프랑스에 가는 것
때문에 되게 예민해져 있으니까
Now it just hit her that she's leaving and she's kind of emotional
자극시키지 않도록 조심해, 알았지?
so no one say anything to set her off, ok?
알았어
왔구나! 안녕?
Hey Rach, hey you.
/ Here she is!
얘들아, 안녕?
Hi you guys!
What did I just say?
내가 그렇게 주의를 줬는데도!!
아니야, 그런게 아니야 괜찮아, 나 괜찮아질거야
No, no, no. It's ok. I'm gonna be fine.
이리 와, 내가 칵테일 만들어 줄게
Come here, I'll make you a drink.
이럴수가, 정말로 레이첼이
떠나는 거라니 믿어지지가 않아
Oh, man! I can't believe she's actually leaving.
How am I gonna say goodbye to Rachel?
내가 어떻게 레이첼한테
작별인사를 해?
I know, she's been such a big part of my life.
맞아, 내 인생의 너무
큰 부분을 차지하고 있어
And it feels like when Melrose Place got cancelled.
이건 마치 연극이 취소됐을 때 같아
I mean... oh, forget it. I miss Melrose Place!
아, 그게 아니라...
에이 뭐 어때!
난 연극 좋아한단 말야!
못 가게 막을 기회가
나한테 있었어
You know, I had a chance to stop her too!
Who loses fifty seven coin tosses in a row?
동전 던지는 데 50번이나
연속으로 지다니 말이 되냐?
Head she wins, tails I lose. Wait a minute...
앞면이면 레이첼이 이기고
뒷면이면 내가 지는건데!
잠깐만...
Yes, Joe?
그래, 조이?
세탁소에서 옷 찾는 걸 깜빡했다
I forgot to pick up my dry cleaning!
괜찮은 거야?
You doing ok?
응, 나아지고 있긴 해
너희, 나 보러 올거지?
Well, I've been better.
You guys are gonna come and visit me, right?
Yes! You know, in six months the Statute of Limitations runs out
그럼! 6개월 뒤면
내 출국 금지 명령 풀리거든?
and I can travel internationally again!
그럼 다시 해외여행 다녀도 돼!
나 너 너무 보고싶을 거 같아
I'm gonna miss you so much.
/ I know.
알아...
You know what? Uhm, I have some goodbye stuff that I wanted to say to each of you
있잖아, 너희 한 명 한 명한테
작별인사 개인적으로 준비했는데
and I was gonna save it until the end of the night, but come here.
송별회 끝나고나서 하려고 했지만
이쪽으로 와봐
Hey, what do you think they're doing in there?
쟤네 저기 가서 뭐할까?
Huh, if I had to guess I'd say Rachel is putting on the bubble wrap
레이첼이 버블랩으로 감고 있고
피비가 때리고 있을 거 같아
and Phoebe is doing the punching.
Oh, Pheebs, I don't even know where to start.
피비, 무슨 말로 시작해야
할지도 모르겠어!
응, 근데 그러기 전에...
Ok well, before you do, I know we weren't supposed to get you going away presents,
우리 작별선물 안주기로 했지만
난 준비한 게 있어
but I do have something for you.
Oh, oh. What is this?
이게 뭐야?
It's a cotton swab with a bit of my saliva on it,
내 침이 끝에 약간
발라져 있는 면봉인데
so that if they perfect the cloning process while you are over there,
네가 프랑스에 있을 동안
복제 인간 프로젝트가 완성되면
you can use the DNA to create your own Pheebs!
이 DNA로 너만의 피비를 만들라구
버리긴 버릴 거지만...
I'm gonna throw this away, but thank you so much for the gesture!
그래도 마음은 너무너무 고마워!
챈들러, 지금 침대방에 들어갔다가
베개에서 이런 걸 발견했어
Chandler? I was just in our bedroom and I found these on my pillow.
Oh, yes. I decided to leave these out for you in case Richard stops by
응, 널 위해 남겨둔 거야
리차드가 찾아와서 노예와
콧수염 놀이 하고싶어질수도 있잖아
and you wanna engage on a little light bondage and moustache play!
What are you talking about? These aren't mine.
무슨 소리 하는 거야
이거 내 꺼 아니야
웃기네! 내 스카프 댄스
이제 볼 생각도 하지마
Oh yeah, right! Good luck getting another scarf dance from me!
That would be a terrible punishment.
그건 너무 끔찍한 벌이야
근데 정말이야
이거 본 적도 없다구
But, I'm serious, I've never seen these before.
Really? Then what are they doing in our guest room?
정말? 그럼 그게 왜
우리 게스트룸에 있었던 거지?
Rachel used to live in that room.
레이첼이 거기 살았었는데
Rachel... with handcuffs! Interesting!
레이첼이...
수갑이라...
흥미로운 걸!
Joey's bare ass!
벗은 조이 엉덩이!
Well played.
고마워, 잘했어
I love you Phoebe.
피비, 사랑해
I love you too. Please don't... Don't turn into... you know... French bitch!
나도 너 사랑해
부탁인데... 변하지 말아줘
못된 프랑스년으로
All right. Well, if I gonna do this, I'd better keep going.
이어서 계속 하는 게 낫겠다
Ok.
/ Ok. Monica?
그래
모니카! 잠깐 들어가서
나랑 얘기 좀 할 수 있을까?
Yeah?
Can you come here with me for a minute?
물론이지
Sure.
너 방수용 마스카라 하고 있니?
Are you wearing waterproof mascara?
No.
아닌데?
넌 망했다
Oh, you're so screwed.
Hey. What was that all about?
대체 무슨 일인거야?
She's gonna say goodbye to each of us individually.
우리 각각한테 개인적으로
작별인사를 할 거래
Are you kidding? Oh my God...
정말이야? 이럴수가...
Yeah, I know, it's gonna be even worse for you... God... Ross,
그러게, 특히 넌 더 심각하지
제대로 울 마음의 준비해둬
get ready to do some serious crying.
Oh, man, I'm not going to be able to handle this.
난 자신이 없어
이제야 내 학생들이 매년 학기말에
무슨 기분인지 알 거 같아
Now I know how my students feel at the end of each year.
나한테 나쁜 수업평가서를 써서
그걸 표현하는 이유도
And why they act out by giving me such bad evaluations.
Mon... Okay... I've gotta... just say what it is I'm gonna say...
그냥, 하고 싶은 말을 할게
None of the amazing things that have happened to me in the last ten years,
지난 십 년동안 내게 있었던
모든 멋진 일들은
would have happened if it wasn't for you.
네가 없었다면 아마
일어나지 않았을거야
누구보다도 넌 나한테
친자매 같은 사람이었어
No-one has been more like a sister to me...
무슨 말인지 알아
I know what you mean. You're like a sister to me too.
너도 내게 있어
친자매 같은 사람이야
너 없이 어떻게 살아...
I wouldn't know what I'm gonna do without you...
You're the best friend I ever had.
......
뭐라구?
What?
I... I... I...
That is so sweet.
고마워!!
이럴수가, 모니카까지 울렸어
Oh no, she took down Monica... And I'm the crier in the family.
내가 우리 집에서
제일 잘 운단 말야
Oh God! I could be next.
이럴수가, 내가
다음 타자일지도 몰라
우리가 대화에 열중하는 것처럼
보이면 말 안 걸지도 몰라
Maybe she won't talk with me if it looks like we're deep in conversation.
그래
Oh, so that thing you said about the thing.
그래서 말인데
네가 그거에 대해서 말한
그것 때문에 난 또
다른 그걸 생각하게 돼
It really made me think about that other thing.
- 레이첼?
- 응
Uh, Rach?
Well it's okay. Chandler is talking to her.
됐다, 챈들러가 얘기하고 있어
그걸 생각하게 됐단 말이지?
I really made you think about that thing uh?
Uh, Rach... I think I have something that belongs to you.
레이첼, 돌려줄 네 물건이
있는 것 같아서
Oh, I'm sure gonna miss pretending to laugh at your weird jokes that I don't get.
이런 너의 이해할 수 없는 농담들을
그냥 좋아하는척 하는 것도 그리울거야
No, no, no... They're really yours. We... found them in your old room.
아니야, 이거 정말 네 꺼야
네가 전에 쓰던 방에서 찾았거든
내 꺼 아니야
Well, these aren't mine. Maybe Monica used to use them with...
어쩌면 모니카가 전에
쓰던 건지도 모르지, 리차..
Don't say Richard!
리차드 얘기 꺼내지 마!
모니카 꺼도 아니고 네 꺼도
아니면 대체 누구 꺼란 말이야?
Well, if they're not Monica's and they're not yours, then whose are they?
Well, I think you're forgetting the kinkiest former resident of that room.
나보다 먼저 살았던 가장 괴팍한
사람의 존재를 잊고 있는 모양이네
Pheebs!
/ Yeah!
피비!
왜?
I think these are yours.
이거 네 꺼 같은데?
내 꺼 아니야
These are not mine... Look how flimsy they are, come on!
내가 이렇게 엉성한 걸
쓸 거 같아?
수도관에 이걸로 남자를
붙들어 맨다고 생각해봐
Good God! You try to hang a guy from a waterpipe with these,
착! 하고 안 잠기잖아
they'll snap like a piece of licorice.
잠깐 둘이서 얘기 좀 할 수 있지?
Can I talk to you alone for a minute?
Sure. You don't really handcuff guys to waterpipes do you?
그럼
정말로 남자들을 수도관에다
수갑으로 채우고 그러진 않지?
넌 그럼 마이크가 뭘로 보이는데?
Where do you think Mike really is?
Oh honey...
챈들러
한 가지만 미리 말해둘게
일단 얘기 시작하면 난 어색해하고
Let me just say something... Because once we get into this,
I'm gonna get all uncomfortable and probably make some stupid joke...
이상한 농담이나 하고
그럴 것 같아서
I just want to say that I... I love you...
해주고 싶은 말은...
사랑해
많이 보고 싶을거야
And, I'm gonna miss you. And I'm so sad that you're leaving.
네가 떠난다니 너무 슬프다
저기 있지
Oh, you know what? Let's not say anything else. I love you.
그냥, 다른 말 하지 말자
나도 널 사랑해
Ooh, not so tight... I'm sorry, just give me one more chance.
더 꽉!
미안, 한 번만 더 기회를 줘
그래
Okay. Oh... Oh!
그냥 가, 아무래도 안되겠다
I'm sor... Just go. Just go. I can't, I can't.
So, I guess you're next. You're ready?
다음은 오빠겠네, 준비됐어?
안된 것 같아
I don't think so.
그럼, 당연하지
난 몇년만에 그렇게 울긴 처음이야
Oh, you're definitely not. I haven't cried like that in years.
You cried yesterday at the six o'clock news.
어제 6시뉴스 보고 울었잖아
정비공한테 사기를 당한 할머니라고!
That old woman was being scammed by her mechanic.
레이첼이 나를 마지막으로 남겨두다니
I can't believe she saved me for last. Why are they taking so long?
왜 이렇게 오래 걸리는 거야?
I don't know. But, God, Joey seems to be handling it surprisingly well.
모르지, 근데 조이는 나름대로
놀랍도록 잘 받아들이고 있는거 같다
No, no, no, no!
안돼! 안돼!
Okay, here we go...
이제 나다
Oh... Well...
저 있잖아
응
Yeah...
I think I'm gonna take off.
나 이제 가볼게
Huh?
뭐?
Oh, you guys. This was an amazing night. Thank you so much.
얘들아, 너무나 멋진 밤이었어
고마워, 사랑해, 잘자
I love you. Good night.
What? I don't get a goodbye?
뭐야?
난 작별인사도 안해줘?
Lucky bastard!
운 좋은 놈 같으니라구!
Unbelievable. She says goodbye to everyone but me.
말도 안돼! 모두한테 다
인사해놓고 나한테는 안해?
Well, maybe she thought that with all of your history it could be,
워낙 둘 사이의 특별한 사연들은
말로 설명못한다고 생각했는지도
you know, implicit.
설명 해줘야겠어!!
Well, it needs to be plicit.
잘 생각해 보자
분명 뭔가 이유가 있을거야
All right, let's think about this. I mean, there's got to be an explanation.
Uh... did you do anything to make her mad?
뭐 레이첼 화나게 한 거 없어?
아니, 그런 건 없는 거 같은데
No, I don't think so.
You know, maybe she was just really spent from our talk. It was pretty intense.
어쩌면 우리들하고 얘기하느라
지쳤는지도 몰라
상당히 열정적이었거든
Yeah. Mine too.
응, 나도
나도 장난 아니었어
Mine was a humdinger
알았어, 알았다구!!
O-kay... I mean, don't I deserve anything? I mean, a few tears, a cursory hug?
나는 아무 인사도 받을
자격이 없는거야?
눈물 한 방울, 포옹 한 번도?
너한테서 말고!!
Not from you!
Ross, if you're this upset, you should go and talk to her.
네가 이렇게나 감정이 상했다면
직접 레이첼한테 가서 말해야 해
And say what? "You owe me a goodbye", I mean, he's got more pride than that.
가서 뭐라 그러라고?
나한테 인사 빚졌다고?
오빠도 자존심이 있지
자존심은 개뿔! 말할거야!!
THE HELL I DO!
I don't get a goodbye?
나한텐 작별인사도 안하는거야?
What?
뭐라구?
Everyone gets a goodbye but me? What have I got to do to get a goodbye, huh?
다른 사람들은 다 작별인사를
받았는데 왜 나만 못받아?
작별인사 받으려면 대체
뭘 해야하는 거지?
Be best friends with you? Uh, go out with you? Have a baby with you?
너의 베스트프렌드가 되어야 하나?
너랑 사귈까?
아기라도 낳아야 하나?
Oh wait a minute, wait a minute, I did all those things.
아, 잠깐 잠깐!!
벌써 다 한 거잖아!!
Ross...
로스...
Oh no, maybe it's me, I'm just not giving you enough credit.
다섯 명한테 작별인사를
한다는 건 어려운 일이니까
Uh, I mean it is difficult to say goodbye to five people.
안녕, 안녕, 안녕, 안녕, 헉!
Uh, goodbye, goodbye, goodbye, goodbye, good... IT'S PHYSICALLY IMPOSSIBLE.
더 이상은 신체 조건상
불가능하잖아?!
You know what? After all we've been through,
우리 둘이 그렇게
많은 일들이 있었는데
I can't believe this is how you want to leave things between us.
너의 떠나는 방식이 이런 거라니
정말 믿을 수가 없어
Have a, have a good time in Paris.
파리에서 잘 살아
I hope Ross isn't too upset.
오빠가 많이 화난 게
아니었으면 좋겠는데
나보다 더 충격받진 않았을 거야
I'm sure he's not more bummed out than I am.
Tell me about it.
그러게 말이야
우리 송별 파티 한 번
재밌게 한다 그치?
Well, you can't say we don't know how to throw a party.
난 이제 가봐야겠다
All right, I think I'm gonna head out.
Uh, where do you think you're going?
어디 가는 건데?
집에 가서 자려고 했는데
I thought I was going home to go to bed,
but I'm sensing there's something less fun for me to do here.
이제 보니 여기 그거 보다
덜 재밌는게 있나보네
We're moving in a couple of days and we've got a lot of packing to do.
우리 며칠 있으면 이사할 건데
아직 짐 쌀 게 많이 있단 말야
좀 도와주면 좋을텐데
It would be great if you guys could pitch in.
Joey and I can finish up in the guest room.
조이랑 나는 게스트룸 정리
마저 할게
그래 그래, 좋은 생각이야
Oh, yeah, yeah, good idea.
그렇게는 안되지
너랑 피비는 거실에서 날 도와줘
Oh no! You and Phoebe are gonna help me in here.
꼭 그렇게 티를 내야됐냐?
You couldn't be cool.
Okay, we're gonna start in the kitchen.
좋아, 부엌부터 시작하자
접시들은 접시 보호 씌워서
열 개씩 박스에 넣어
Plates get put into plate protectors and stacked ten to a box.
은제품들은 고무밴드로 묶은 다음
버블랩으로 씌워, 알겠어?
The silverware gets bundled in rubber bands and then bubble wrapped. Got it?
그래
Yeah.
좋아
Good! Now I need you to be careful and efficient.
자, 이제부터 아주 조심스럽고
효과적으로 일해주길 바래
And remember, if I am harsh with you, it is only because you are doing it wrong.
그리고 잊지마
내가 너희한테 신경질을 낸다면
그건 다 너희가
잘못하고 있기 때문이야
Hey Mon, I think I figured out whose handcuffs they are.
모니카, 그 수갑 주인이
누군지 알아낸 거 같아
정말? 어떻게?
You did? How?
Well, I was cleaning out the closet and I found some pictures of them... being used.
옷장 치우고 있었는데
사진들을 찾았어
이 수갑들이 사용되고 있을 때 사진들
Oh my God! Let me see.
맙소사! 보여줘!
Who's that dirty old lady?
이 추한 할머니는 누구야?
Monica's grandmother.
모니카네 할머니야
Nana liked it rough!
할머니 좀 노셨네!
안녕하세요!
Hi!
/ Hey!
안녕하세요!
Come on here, have a seat.
앉아요
How was your night?
어젯밤엔 어땠어요?
Oh, it was okay. I went to a movie with my cousin and then out for dinner.
괜찮았죠, 사촌언니랑 영화보러
갔다가 밥도 먹으러 갔어요
We went to this place that had... Ooh... Hoo... ooh...
어떤 레스토랑이 있는데...
Anyway, they had these really amazing cheeseburgers.
어쨌든 그 레스토랑 치즈버거가
정말 환상이더라구요
Erica, are you okay?
에리카, 괜찮은 거에요?
괜찮아요
너무 많이 먹어서 그런가봐요
Yeah, you know, maybe I ate too much. I keep getting these stomach aches.
자꾸 배가 아프거든요
몇 분마다 한 번씩 아프고 그래요
They come and go like every few minutes.
Oh my God!
오, 이럴수가!
뭐 어때
그냥 소화제 먹으면 되지
Relax! We just get her some antacids.
She doesn't have a stomach ache, she's in labor.
이건 그냥 배가 아픈게 아니야
진통이 오는 거라고!!
Oh my God!
이런!
병원에 데려가야 해!!
Yeah, you got to get to the hospital.
All right, Chandler get the coats. Erica let's go.
챈들러, 코트 가져와!
에리카, 가요!
피비랑 조이, 짐 계속 싸!!
Phoebe and Joey, keep packing! Oh my God we're gonna have a baby.
아기가 태어날 거에요
이럴 수가! 아기가 태어날 거야!
All right. We're gonna have a baby! OH MY GOD, WE'RE GONNA HAVE A BABY!
Oh God, oh God, I got to sit down, I got to sit down. Ooh!
이럴 수가... 좀 앉아야겠어
모니카, 다 괜찮을 거야
Honey, it's gonna be okay.
모니카, 당신을 할 수 있어요!
심호흡 해요!
You can do this. Just breathe.
Okay, okay... Okay, I feel a little better.
알았어요
좀 나아진 것 같아
Ooh! Are you sure?
정말 괜찮은 거에요?
Oh... Yes, I'm sure. Oh honey, let's go. Okay bye everyone.
그럼요, 난 괜찮아요!
얘들아 다녀 올게!
챈들러! 잠깐만!
Chandler, wait, wait, wait...
What?
왜?
좀 여유가 생기면, 그 치즈버거
어디서 먹었냐고 좀 물어봐줘
If you get a second, find out where she got that cheeseburger.
You really think I didn't say goodbye to you because I don't care?
내가 정말 네가 소중하지 않아서
너한테만 작별인사 안했다 생각해?
That's what it seemed like.
나한테는 그렇게 보였어
I cannot believe that after ten years, you do not know ONE thing about me.
이렇게 10년이 지나도
네가 나에 대해 하나도
모른다니 믿을 수가 없어!
Fine, then why didn't you say something?
좋아, 그럼 아무 것도
말 안한 이유가 뭐야?
Because it is too damn hard Ross.
왜냐면 그게 너무
미치도록 힘들어서야, 로스!
I can't even begin to explain to you how much I'm gonna miss you.
내가 널 얼마나 많이 그리워할 건지
그 설명의 시작조차
나는 할 수가 없어
When I think about not seeing you every day, it makes me not want to go...
내가 널 매일같이 보지
못 할거란 걸 생각하면
가기가 싫어져, 알겠어?
Okay, so if you think that I didn't say goodbye to you
네가 다른 얘들만큼 의미가 없어서
작별인사를 안한거라고 생각한다면
because you don't mean as much to me as everybody else,
you're wrong. It's because you mean more to me.
잘못 생각하는 거야
네 의미가 너무 커서 못한거야
So there, all right, there's your goodbye... Oh!
그래, 이거야
이게 너에 대한 작별인사야!
Rach!
레이첼!
What?
왜!
이럴 수는, 너 이럴 수는...
You keep, you keep... You can't...
뭐가!
WHAT?
더 넣어
A little more.
Okay.
알았어
좀 더, 좀 더, 조금만 더~
A little more, a little more. A little more... All right. Okay, all right, let's do this.
좋아, 됐어
이제 해보자
준비됐어?
All right, ready?
응, 온 힘을 다해 힘껏 쳐
Yeah. All right, now give me your best shot.
All right, here it goes...
자, 간다
하나도 보호가 안되네
Doesn't work...